Guide to the Samuel Roth papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Samuel Roth Papers,
1907-1994
[Bulk Dates: 1910-1979].
Roth, Samuel, 1893-1974.
25.2 linear ft. (54 boxes: 51 document boxes, 2 oversize flat boxes 1 record carton)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1463
6913670
Samuel Roth (1893-1974)—writer, publisher, entrepreneur, and all-around schemer—is best known for publishing unauthorized excerpts of James Joyce's Ulysses in the United States, and for being the plaintiff in a landmark case before the United States Supreme Court that redefined what constitutes obscene material unprotected by the First Amendment. The Samuel Roth Papers contain annotated books, manuscripts, court documents, business records, copyright statements, unpublished typescripts (by Roth and others), publishing advertisements and materials, as well as correspondence.
Biographical Note
During his career Samuel Roth (1893-1974) established bookstores in New York City that published and sold books, magazines, and erotica, and operated a mail order operation that defied Post Office censors for two decades. He founded two literary magazines, namely Beau--the first American "men's magazine--and Two Worlds. As a publisher, Roth was frequently accused of violating the copyrights of authors such as D.H. Lawrence and James Joyce, and was responsible for the first, unauthorized editions of Lady Chatterley's Lover and Ulysses. After Joyce published the "International Protest" against Samuel Roth in 1927, a petition signed by over one hundred of the world's elite artists and public figures, Roth became a pariah in the publishing world. Falling back upon his ingenuity and keen sense of salesmanship, Roth ended up in the mail-order pornography business, creating Good Times and American Aphrodite: A Quarterly for the Fancy Free. He published a critical treatise on Herbert Hoover, The Strange Career of Mr. Hoover Under Two Flags (1931), which sold well and thus may have helped defeat the President in 1932 In 1951 he issued My Sister and I, purportedly a memoir by Nietzsche about his incestuous relationship with his sister.
A self-taught writer, Roth wrote poetry and essays throughout his life. His early poetry won praise from Edwin Arlington Robinson, Maurice Samuel, Marie Syrkin, Harriet Monroe, Israel Zangwill, and Louis Untermeyer. "Samuel Roth publicized himself as a literary Johnny Appleseed, bringing to ordinary Americans the modern literature of two continents, despite its sexual explicitness. He was also a master of prurient advertising of borderline mail order sex pulps and sensational human interest stories. He put himself in the direct line of fire that municipal, state and federal law enforcement officials and moral entrepreneurs reserved for pariah capitalists," said Jay Gertzman, Professor Emeritus at Mansfield University and author of Bookleggers and Smuthounds: The Trade in Erotica, 1920-1940. "Researchers will find Roth's archives valuable not only for a study of Roth but of New York publishing history and the history of censorship," continued Gertzman.
Roth last achieved notoriety in 1957 as the appellant in the Supreme Court case, Roth v. United States. The minority decision in the case opened the way to Constitutional protection for expression previously censored for indecency, and became a template for the liberalizing First Amendment decisions of the 1960s.
Scope and Content
The Samuel Roth Papers contain annotated books, manuscripts, court documents, business records, copyright statements, unpublished typescripts (by Roth and others), publishing advertisements and materials, as well as correspondence. Among Roth's own works are his poetry, plays, and fiction, including The Transfiguration, an epic Roth thought would bring him fame and success as a writer. Both his unpublished autobiography, Count Me Among the Missing, and his daughter's unfinished memoir of her father, In a Plain Brown Wrapper (as well as her extensive research materials), are also included in the collection.
For certain works, Samuel Roth employed pseudonyms such as David Zorn, and his most frequently used nom de guerre, Norman Lockridge. Interestingly, he often used the latter name to clandestinely correspond with people, such as T.S. Eliot and Ernest Hemingway, who had signed Joyce's International Protest against him.
Blending both the personal and the professional, the Correspondence series houses Roth's numerous prison letters sent from Lewisburg while serving his multiple sentences. Usually addressed to his wife Pauline, Roth shares his thoughts regarding prison life, his numerous literary undertakings, and advises Pauline regarding business matters. Many of Roth's early professional correspondents (1915-1925) are major names of twentieth century modernist literature and poetics, that include: Floyd Dell; (1917): William Stanley Braithwaite, John Gould Fletcher, James Oppenheim, Edgar Lee Masters, George Edward Woodberry, Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Lizette Woodsworth Reese and William Roe Benet; (1918-1919): Jessie Rittenhouse, Shaemus O'Sheel, Louise Bryant, H.D.; (1920-1921): Arthur Symons, Israel Zangwill, T.S. Eliot, Clement Wood, Carl Van Doren, George Bernard Shaw, Aldous Huxley, Edward Gosse, J.C. Squire, Ezra Pound, Leonard Woolf; (1922-25): Sylvia Beach, Avrahm Yarmolinsky, John Herrmann, Ezra Pound, Bryher (Annie Winifred Ellerman), James Branch Cabell, Ford Madox Ford, Harriet Shaw Weaver, Dorothy M. Richardson, Arthur Stanley Eddington, Upton Simclair, Leslie Gordon Philips, Gershon Legman.
The calendar series, part of Roth's editorial efforts, shows how much Roth was, in many ways, ahead of his time in regards to the publishing business and its many sales gimmicks. Similarly, the Publishing series as a whole represents a great testament to Roth's advertising acumen, offering a fascinating behind-the-scenes glimpse of the self-publishing business in the years following World War II.
Roth's legal troubles encompassed many years. The prepared packets seem to have, in most cases, been created on-the-go during the trials, while some may have been put together at a later date.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in five series
Series I: Writings, 1907-1994
Sub-series I.1: Writings by Samuel Roth, 1914-1969
Sub-sub-series I.1.1: Edited Calendars, Day Books, and Other Collected Works, 1932-1937
Sub-series I.2: Writings by Adelaide Roth, 1970s-1994
Sub-sub-series I.2.1: Research Materials, 1950s-1990s
Sub-series I.3: Writings by Others, 1907-1986
Series II: Legal Documents, 1926-1969
Sub-series II.1: Notes and Prepares Legal Files, 1931-1959
Sub-series II.2: Legal Correspondence, 1926-1969
Sub-series II.3: Court Documents, 1947-1961
Series III: Correspondence, 1909-1993
Sub-series III.1: Samuel Roth, 1909-1971
Sub-series III.2: Adelaide Kugel Roth, 1974-1993
Series IV: Publishing, 1919-1974
Sub-series IV.1: Promotional Materials, 1919-1960s
Sub-series IV.2: Legal and Financial Files, 1930-1974
Sub-series IV.3: Accessories and Business Materials, 1930-1972
Sub-series IV.4: American Aphrodite, 1915-1994
Series V: Personal, 1915-1994
Subjects
Joyce, James, 1882-1941--Criticism and interpretation.; Joyce, James, 1882-1941.--Ulysses.; Joyce, James, 1882-1941--Periodicals.; Kugel, Adelaide.; Lawrence, D.H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930.--Lady Chatterley's lover.; Lockridge, Norman--pseudonym.; Roth, Adelaide.; Roth, Pauline.; Roth, Samuel, 1893-1974.; Zorn, David--pseudonym.; Geographic; Booksellers and bookselling.; Copyright--United States.; Erotica--Periodicals.; Erotica--United States.; Juvenile delinquency--United States.; Mail-order business.; Obscenity (Law)--United States.; Obscenity (Law)--United States--Cases.; Obscenity (Law)--United States--Periodicals.; Pornography--Law and legislation--United States--Cases.; Pornography--United States.; Publishers and publishing.; Genre; Occupation; American Aphrodite: A Quarterly for the Fancy-Free.; Beau.; Good Times.; Two Worlds.; Two Worlds Monthly.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located on-site.
This collection has no restrictions. Much of the correspondence in boxes 35-38, however, is extremely fragile and therefore access to this material will be determined on a case-by-case basis.
Acquisition
Bettina Hirsch, James Kugel, and Candace A. Kugel Gift 2006
- Series I: Writings, 1907-1990s
  This, the largest series in the collection, includes mostly unpublished pieces by Samuel Roth, as well as collected works he edited; drafts of his daughter Adelaide Roth's memoir and essays, in addition to her extensive research materials; typescripts and holographs by various hands that either never made it to publication or are versions of material that was once published by one of Roth's many imprints.
  - I.1. Subseries: Writings by Samuel Roth, 1914-1969
    Consisting mostly of typescripts, this large sub-series is brimming with Roth's multiple unpublished works, but also contains some copies of published pieces. Along with various short stories, plays, fictionalized histories, are multiple drafts of Roth's last autobiography Count Me Among the Missing. Also in this sub-series is an epic work entitled The Transfiguration. Other works include The Hebrew Melodies of Heinrich Heine, The Kingdom, a long series of psalms. Some manuscript pages have not been identified and remain untitled.
    - "Across the Street," 1960s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Anti Semitism as a Necessary Condition in the Jewish World," 1930s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Broomstick Brigade--Play, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A Career in Publishing--Re: Roth publications, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Chapter One: The Arrest", Undated (author uncertain) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Count Me Among the Missing
      - "Adrift in London"--Extract for Journal of Modern Literature, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Drafts
        - 1-414, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 7 to 8)
        - 1-14, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - 2-280, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - 2-293, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - 29-96--Incomplete, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - 64-400, 1969, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 1 to 2)
        - 187-400, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        - "Count Me Original Typewritten,"--74-414, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 4 to 5)
        - Loose Pages, Undated (with binder cover) (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - The Natural History of Mishillim--1-396, 1969 (1 of 2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Version of "Chapter 2," 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "The Dancing Priests of Isis," Undated (author uncertain) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "A Definition of Existentialism," Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "The Death of Dr Bell", Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - The Diary
      - "Bashkirtseff," Undated (author uncertain) (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - "Marie Bashkierstsoff," Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Getaway
      - 141 pages, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - A Novelty--141 pages, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - [Bound]--114 pages, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - By Norman Lockridge--174 pages, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Incomplete, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Prison Story--16 pages, Undated (labeled "for Lou") (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - The Hebrew Melodies of Heinrich Heine
      - Arranged Pages, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Carbon Copy, 1960s (with notations) (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - "for Chig," Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Incomplete Drafts, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Introduction--With Irish's "Happiness," Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "in a Redaction by Samuel Roth," 1960s (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Loose Pages, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Helen Thy Beauty, 145 pages, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Heliogabalus
      - 341 Pages, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Annotated,1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Annotated--297 pages, 1962, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 5 to 6)
        (Fragile Material)
      - By Norman Lockridge,1960s (1 of 2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - By Norman Lockridge,1960s (2 of 2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - 15-236--End,1960s (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - HERZL: A Play--Half-Filled Notebook, Undated (Dedicated to Israel Zangwill) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "The Hunt"--In The Hebrew Standard, 1914 (with letter) (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - "If I take the Witness Stand," 1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - The Immor(t)al David, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "In Passing", 1960s (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "In the Days of Caligula"--From “Agrippa," 1-19, Undated (author uncertain) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Ishmael: A Portrait," 1959 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Jack the Ripper--With Preface, 1950s (author uncertain) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - -With Illustrations, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - The Jewish Princess, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - The Jewish Proposal--Play, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kangaroo Court, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - The Kingdom
      - General, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - A Book of Israeli Davidia, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - A Book of Israeli Psalms, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - The Israeli Book of Psalms--With Letter, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - The Israeli Book of Psalms, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Israeli Davidia, 1960s, (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 1 to 3)
      - "by David Zorn," 1960s (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Out of Order, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 5)
        (some pages Re: Heinrich Heine book)
    - The Leader, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "The Man Who Loved to Kill Women," Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Meshullum Brings News from the True World--Incomplete, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - General
      - “Bridgehead Books,” Various Drafts, Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - "Last Writings," 1940-1960 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - "SR Writing & Latest Circs,” 1960s (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - "Stuff of Memoirs," Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - "Trifles," Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Early Published Writings, 1918-1920 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Loose Pages--Various Texts, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - "Misc. MS," 1965, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Poems, Undated (with notes and illustrations) (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Poems--Unidentified, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "Moon Over Broadway," "Excess Baggage," 1948 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Murder at Sycamore Lodge, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Naked Woman: A Play in Four Acts
      - Drafts, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 2 to 3)
      - "The Heavenly Babe: Synoptic Adaptation of the Play," 1928 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Natalie," 1929 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - The New Wisdom--With Pages From Prince Hal, My Friend Yeshea, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "Re: Nightmare Alley," 1950s (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Notebooks
      - "Books-Music," "JR," Undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - "Drama in Syracuse," Undated (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - "I am composing these notes late in the summer," 1933 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - "Idealists of East Broadway: Stories," and "Swine: A Novel," 1920s (some glued pages) (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - "Jot-a-Lot," "Valley Rendez-Vous," Undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - "My Ten Nights in a Dance Hall," Undated (mostly blank) (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - "National Diary 1922"--Prose and List of Authors, 1922 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - "The Natural History of David Zorn, Undated (mostly blank) (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - "The Wit and Wisdom of the Nations," Undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - "Notes for an Informal Talk," 1965 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Nutscha Sonnets," Undated (out of order) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "Open Plumbing"--From Two Worlds, 1920s (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Over Night: A Comedy of Minor Social Terrors, Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Picasso for Children--Prototype, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - The Poet's Sufferings--Pamphlet, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "Preparing for Peace"--Poems, Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Prince Hal and the Jewish Proposal, A Drama
      - Draft, 1960 (with drawing of Jesus) (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Draft, 1960 (incomplete) (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - The Princess Berenice: A Biography, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 11 to 12)
    - "A Quarter of a Century of Literary Criticism," Undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - San Quentin
      - "Corrected portion of San Quentin Novel" (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - "Incomplete San Quentin," Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "Sodom"--185-231, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Sodom's Hot," 1960s (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "Songs out of Season"--33 Poems, Undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Star of the West
      - By David Zorn, 1930s (incomplete) (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Unidentified--2-263, Undated (was with the pages of Star of the West) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Stone Walls Do Not, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "The Summoner," Undated (out of order) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Summer Thunder, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - The Transfiguration
      - Draft--414-829, 1930s (1 of 2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Draft--414-829, 1930s (1 of 2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Volume 1--1-213, 1930s, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Volume 2--214-428, 1930s (with Prologue) (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Volume 1--1-367, 1930s, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Unidentified Manuscripts
      - 21-36, 39,45-65,68-75,96-107,473-726, Undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - 29-266, Undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified Story, Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Untitled Series of Numbered Poems--Incomplete, Undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Untitled Typescript--Incomplete, Undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Western Star--111 pages, 1930s (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - A Woman A Day: A Novel, Undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Young Berenice, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 1 to 2)
    - 1.1. Sub-subseries: Edited Calendars, Day-Books, and Other Collected Works, 1932-1937
      This small sub-sub-series gathers Roth's editorial efforts.
      - A Calendar of Comfort for Catholics--Gilbert Keith Chesterton, 1930s (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - A Calendar of Courage for Music-Lovers--Romain Rolland, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - A Calendar of Sorrow for Cynics--Anatole France, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Day-Book of Protest for Protestants--George Santayana, 1930s (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - A Day-Book of Solace for Scientists--Alexis Carrel, Bound With The World of Balzac, 1930s (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - One Man's Adventure: Being the Life, Thoughts and Adventures of Arthur Symons, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Plain English, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Richard Aldington's A Dream in the Luxembourg--102 Poems by Various Authors, Undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - The Tender Passion: In Songs--101 Poems by Various Authors, Undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - I.2. Subseries: Writings by Adelaide Roth, 1970s-1990s
    Included here are chapters and drafts of In a Plain Brown Wrapper, Adelaide Roth’s unpublished memoir, and Wroth Wrackt Joyce, her essay on Samuel Roth and James Joyce, and other writings, working drafts, some with corrections. The folders listed as "Drafts" represent the versions of her memoir that were found in separate individual boxes. The "Chapters" folders were found in folders titled by Adelaide Roth and many of the documents of these folders bear Adelaide's annotations. Chapters found together were kept together. Efforts have been made to name folders according to chapter titles, unless Adelaide Roth had already given a given folder a title. In the latter case, the title was put in quotation marks.
    - "Joyce"--"for Article on FW," Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Mixed Chapters of Plain Brown Wrapper and Wroth Wrackt Joyce, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 3 to 4)
    - "MS: Joyce/Roth," Undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Plain Brown Wrapper
      - Chapters
        - General, (4 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 6 to 9)
        - 1932, Undated (annotated) (Box 16, Folder 10)
        - "96 Willett Street," Undated (letter "to my cousins") (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - "Building the Case & Conviction," Undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
        - "Columbia" to "Two Worlds Quarterly," 1989 (Box 17, Folder 3)
        - "The End of the Line" to "Friday Nights at Home," Undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
        - "Enter the F.B.I." to "Number 5079," Undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
        - "Fifty Glenwood Avenue" to "The Ansonia," 1987 (Box 17, Folder 6)
        - "Friendships," Undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
        - "The Literati" to "The Making of JML," 1987 (Box 18, Folder 1)
        - "Love S," "Mr. Roth," and "1939," 1988 (Box 18, Folder 2)
        - "The Mayflower" to "Number 5079," 1988 (Box 18, Folder 3)
        - "Mostly Re: Trial," Undated (Annotated) (Box 18, Folder 4)
        - "Wrath Against Joyce" to "Sumner Sets a Trap," Undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Drafts
        - Computer Printouts, Undated (1 of 9 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 6)
        - Computer Printouts, Undated (5 of 9 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1 to 5)
        - Computer Printouts, Undated (3 of 9 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 1 to 3)
        - Typewritten, Undated (with notes)(3 of 5 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 4 to 6)
        - Typewritten, Undated (with notes)(2 of 5 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Wroth Wrackt Joyce
      - "1st Draft A.R. Kugel," Undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - "Article," Undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Drafts, 1992, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 5 to 6)
      - "Joyce, etc 1928," Undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Offprints, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - "Sam Roth's Odyssey with Ulysses," Undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Various Versions, Undated (annotated) (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - I.2.1. Sub-subseries: Research Materials, 1950s-1990s (Box 22)
      Gathered here is research material that Adelaide Roth amassed while working on her memoir, and on her work regarding Samuel Roth's publishing of Ulysses and other Joyce texts in Two Worlds Monthly. Included here are correspondence, clippings, photocopies of archival materials, articles, and notebooks. The titles of folders originally labeled by Adelaide Roth are in quotation marks.
      - Alger Hiss, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - "Archive I: Letters",Undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Archival Research, 1980s, (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Autobiographical Statement by Samuel Roth, Undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - "Backup for Joyce/Roth Agreement," Undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Biographical Information on Roth, Undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Catalogue of Roth Imprints--by Jay Gertzman, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Chronology and Inventory of Letters, Undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Clippings
        - General, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 10)
        - "Newspaper Clippings and Xeroxes," 1910s-1990s (with list of contents) (Box 22, Folder 11)
        - Obituaries, 1940s-1970s (Box 22, Folder 12)
        - Publisher's Weekly, July 22, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 13)
        - "A Reporter at Large," The New Yorker, September 16, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Computer Instructions, Undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - "Disks," Undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - Essay on Roth by Arthur Sainer, Undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - "Frank Tannenbaum," Undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - "Gertzman (Catalogues, Articles)," 1980s (Box 22, Folder 19)
      - "Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center," 1990 (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - Hotel Floor Plans, Undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - "Inventory List of Roth Pubs," Undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - Index Cards, Undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - "INFO," 1980s, Undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - "John Quinn," Undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - "John Soclum"--With Correspondence, Undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - "Joyce," Undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Kefauver Hearings, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 5)